

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Mihiri P.D.S Samaraweera
- Malabe , Sri Lanka
- www.Mihiri.scholar.com
- in www.Mihiri.linkdin.com

CONTACT

- +94 777340657
- <u>mihiri.s@sliit.lk</u>

SOFT SKILLS

- Teaching & Facilitation
- Communication
- Mentoring & Guidance
- Time Management
- Problem Solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming and Development
- Software Engineering and Systems
- Tools and Frmeworks

MIHIRI P.D.S SAMARAWEERA

ASSISTANT LECTURER

PROFILE

Experienced academic professional with a strong background in Information Technology, specializing in both theoretical and practical aspects of the field. Skilled in delivering lectures, conducting workshops, and mentoring students to achieve their full potential in various IT subjects. Always wanted to become good facilitator to students and also in love with what I am doing right now.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Department of Information Technology | SLIITAssistant Lecturer at SLIIT

2023- PRESENT

- Delivering Lectures and Tutorials to facilitate student learning, Subjects: DSA, SE, IWT, FA, ITP, SPM, IP
- Conducting Workshops
- Assist in ongoing Research Projects under senior academics
- Strong oral communication skills to present lectures and answer questions
- Staying updated with the latest developments in the subject area
- Provide one-on-one Academic Mentoring and Consultation
- Guide students through Coursework, Projects, and Assignments
- Mark/grade Assignments, Quizzes, and Lab reports
- Help to arrange Academic Events like workshops and other student competitions
- · Attend Training, Workshops to improve teaching
- Support Exam Coordination

Department of Information Technology | SLIIT

2021-2023

Academic Instructor

- Help in maintaining Learning Management Systems (LMS) with study materials
- Delivering Practical Sessions to Facilitate student learning
- Staying updated with the latest developments in the subject area
- Exam Invigilation
- Guide students in completing assignments and projects
- Evaluate lab work, assignments, and project submissions
- · Answering students' questions and providing support

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sri Lanka Telecom PLC

2020 FEB - 2020 AUG

Trainee Software Engineer

- Event Management Portal
- Technologies: JAVA, MYSQL, HTML, CSS
- Both Frontend and Backend implementation

EDUCATION

B.Sc(hons) in Information Technology Specialising in Information Technology

2017 - 2021

SLIIT University

• GPA - 3.24

MSc in Information Technology -Enterprise Application Development 2023 - PRESENT

SLIIT University

· Still Reading

CERTIFICATES

Teaching Methodology in Higher Education ISO 9001:2015 Certified

Advanced Certificate in English Language NIBM

Dean's List Certificate
4th Year

IWMS Examinations

PUBLICATION

Gesture driven smart home solution for bedridden people

SEPTEMBER 2020

SLIIT University

- Research paper published in 35th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering 2020
- Presented at 21-25 September 2020, Melbourne, Australia
- ACM Digital Library: https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3417113.3422998
- IEEE Xplore: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9319303

EXTRACURRICULAR AND OUTREACH

Conducting CodeFest School workshops

SLIIT University

Active Committee Member in School CodeFest Coding Contest - Junior Coding Category

SLIIT University

Conducting Web Development Lab Sessions and participate in Evaluations
Nalanda Campus - IUHS

2024 FEB

Participate in SLIIT Open Days

REFERENCES

Dr. Nathali Silva

Assistant Professor | Faculty of Computing | SLIIT

Phone: +94 769496649 **Email:** nathali.s@sliit.lk

Ms. Jenny Krishara

Senior Lecturer | Faculty of Computing | SLIIT

Phone: +94 715710178 Email: jenny.k@sliit.lk